{
    "books": [
      {
        "fileUrl": "/pdfs/X/Science/Science Textbook.pdf",
        "questions": [
            {
                "question": "Which of the following does not involve a chemical reaction?",
                "options": [
                    "Melting of candle wax on heating",
                    "Burning of candle wax when heated",
                    "Digestion of food in our body",
                    "Process of respiration"
                ],
                "correct_option": "Melting of candle wax on heating"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following statements is true for acids?",
                "options": [
                    "Sour and change blue litmus to red",
                    "Bitter and change red litmus to blue",
                    "Bitter and change blue litmus to red",
                    "Sour and change red litmus to blue"
                ],
                "correct_option": "Sour and change blue litmus to red"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which of the following oxide(s) of iron would be obtained on prolonged reaction of iron with steam?",
                "options": [
                    "Fe2O3 and Fe3O4",
                    "Fe2O3",
                    "FeO",
                    "Fe3O4"
                ],
               "correct_option": "Fe3O4"
            },
            {
                "question": "Pentane has the molecular formula C5H12. It has?",
                "options": [
                    "16 covalent bonds",
                    "17 covalent bonds",
                    "12 covalent bonds",
                    "5 covalent bonds"
                ],
               "correct_option": "16 covalent bonds"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which part of alimentary canal receives bile from the liver?",
                "options": [
                    "Oesophagus",
                    "Large intestine",
                    "Stomach",
                    "Small intestine"
                ],
                "correct_option": "Small intestine"
            },
            {
                "question": "Which gland secretes the growth hormone?",
                "options": [
                    "Adrenal",
                    "Hypothalamus",
                    "Pituitary gland",
                    "Thyroid"
                ],
                "correct_option": "Pituitary gland"
            },
            {
                "question": "Male reproductive organ in flowering plant is?",
                "options": [
                    "Ovary",
                    "Stamen",
                    "Corolla",
                    "Carpel"
                ],
                "correct_option": "Stamen"
            },
            {
                "question": "An object at a distance of 30 cm from a concave mirror gets its image at the same point. The focal length of the mirror is?",
                "options": [
                    "+15 cm",
                    "-15 cm",
                    "30 cm",
                    "-30 cm"
                ],
                "correct_option": "-15 cm"
            },
            {
                "question": "Direction of rotation of a coil in electric motor is determined by?",
                "options": [
                    "Faraday law of electromagnetic induction",
                    "Fleming’s right hand rule",
                    "Fleming’s left hand rule",
                    "None of above"
                ],
                "correct_option": "Fleming’s left hand rule"
            },
            {
                "question": "If a grasshopper is eaten by a frog, then the energy transfer will be from ?",
                "options": [
                    "secondary consumer to primary consumer",
                    "primary consumer to secondary consumer ",
                    "producer to primary consumer",
                    "producer to decomposer"
                ],
                "correct_option": "primary consumer to secondary consumer"
            }
        ]
        
      }
    ]
  }
  